# JONATHAN TAYLOR

Enthusiastic computer science specialist with 6 years of experience in Java standard API libraries as well as JavaFX GUI and Spring for REST services. Python selenium web scraping, designing responsive web pages with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and jQuery, and creating a functional database in SQL. Knowledge of packet analysis, packet filtering, firewall rules, IDS, and IPS.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Jan 2020 — Sep 2020 | Student AV/Tech Assistant | Troy University

• Setting up equipment for events on campus

## 2020 | Auburn Hackathon | Auburn, AL

• creating a game in C++ that disturbs PC functionality

# 2019 | Troy Hackathon | Troy, AL

working on frontend that meets backend of model adoption website

# 2018 | UAB Programming Competition | Birmingham, AL

• timely solving various programming problems using Java

#### June 2017 — Present | Cashier/Cook | McAlister's Deli

• helping and engaging with customers and team members

# December 2021 — May 2022 | Computer Science Club Web Master

• Improving and maintaining the Computer Science club website

# **PROJECTS**

#### SQL Restaurant Database | GitHub Repository: sql-database-project

• Complete with functions, triggers, and EER Diagrams

## Spring 5 Web App | GitHub Repository: spring-5-web-app

• Library database, Spring Boot, Maven, Java 17

# Japan Travel Website | GitHub Repository: japan-travel-website

• Booking Flights, PHP, SQL, XAMPP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

## RELEVANT COURSES

# Intro to Database Systems | CS-4420-XTIA

• Using SQL, EER diagrams, and the relational model

#### Analysis of Algorithms | CS-3329-TSAA

 Dynamic programming and Graph algorithms; Bellman-Ford, Djikstra, and Johnson algorithms uploaded to GitHub Repository: Java and contributed to github.com/TheAlgorithms/Java

#### **Cyber Security Technique & Practice | CS-4455-TSAA**

 Exploring various tools and techniques used to attack and secure systems; Wireshark, pfSense, IPTables, etc.

## Software Engineering | CS-3332-XTIA

• Scrum and Agile development



jontaylor091@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/jonathan-taylor-746ba8195/



## **EDUCATION**

Troy University, Troy, Alabama

Bachelor of Science Computer Science Minor in Cyber Security

## RELEVANT SKILLS

Java [Very Proficient] (6 years)

C++ [Proficient] (3 years)

Python [Some Proficiency]

SQL

PHP

Spring Framework

GitHub

Kali Linux

**Conversational French**